Guide to the Alaska Commercial Company Records, 1868-1940 JL006
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Alaska Commercial Company Records,
1868-1940
JL006
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
18.0 Linear feet
Alaska Commercial Company
Materials withdrawn from the collection
Duplicates
Scope and Content
The collection consists of loose papers and volumes of general accounts. The first group in the series of loose material consists of sundry papers and documents from 1888 to 1897, and were originally found together as such. The second group contains three numbered subseries, which are also in their original order; these are headed accounts. The subject matter of these accounts is varied and with no obvious order other than chronological; the papers have been listed with their numbers preserved as they were numbered in the envelopes in which they were found. The series are H-1 to H-30, I-2 to I-17, and 1-629. These papers are dated from 1890 to 1939; some numbers are missing, which the donor stated at the time the collection was presented to this library. There is a rough progression in date, and the subjects include: individual accounts and collections, legal documents, (bills of sale, contracts, charters), correspondence, and statements. The third group of papers are financial reports from Unalaska and date from 1936 to 1940 and the last group consists of annual financial reports and lists of stockholders of the Alaska Commercial Company.
The volumes include (under the name of the Alaska Commercial Company): stock certificates, stock journals and ledger, general ledgers, private ledgers and journals, a fur book and fur average record, and a Yukon Saw Mill ledger. Volumes for the Northern Commercial Company and the Northern Navigation Company are very much the same: minutes (three volumes for each company), stock certificates and journals, private ledgers and journals, and trial balances. The Alaska Commercial Company volumes are dated from 1868 to 1940; the Northern Commercial Company, 1906-1926; and the Northern Navigation Company, 1905-1921.
The records of the Alaska Commercial Company are of particular interest to anyone seeking information about the business activity of the early Pacific Coast, mainly in the business and accounting activities of the company, rather than in the managerial or executive area. Minutes of the board of directors are included among the material for the Northern Commercial Company and the Northern Navigation Company, but not for the Alaska Commercial Company itself, which eliminates a detailed look at this aspect of the business. Because of the very similar nature of the activities of the Alaska Commercial and the Northern Commercial Companies, however, the existence of these minutes is a valuable source for information concerning many aspects of the entire business.
Historical Note
The history of the Alaska Commercial Company actually begins in 1776, when, under the flag of Czarist Russia, Gregor Shelikof and Ivan Golikof formed a trading company in the Alaskan territory that was under Russian rule. In 1799 they received trading privileges on the western coast of the United States and became the Russian-American Company. After the 1867 purchase of Alaska by the United States, the firm of Hutchison, Kohl & Company, including Hayward Hutchison, William Kohl, and Louis Sloss, bought the Russian-American Company. In 1868, Sloss, Lewis Gerstle, and A. Wassermann bought this company, although Hutchison, Kohl & Company was in simultaneous existence and under the same ownership until 1872, when the new company paid off the purchase. This new company, formed in 1868, was called the Alaska Commercial Company, and did business under this name until 1901. In that year, because of increasing competition in the sealskin trade, the Alaska Commercial Company merged with the International Mercantile Marine Company and Alaska Goldfields, Ltd., to form two new companies, the Northern Navigation Company and the Northern Commercial Company. The original owners of the Alaska Commercial Company, Louis Sloss, Gerstle, etc. carried on the business under the name of the Northern Commercial Company. Shortly afterwards, W.J. Erskine bought some of the old Alaska Commercial Company boats and set up a small successor to the Company in certain areas of Alaska.
Volney Richmond, since 1910 a Company supervisor, was one of several employees to purchase the Northern Commercial Company in 1922, thus leaving the functioning of the Company virtually unchanged, except in legal ownership. The Northern Commercial Company is still very much in existence today, with its executive offices in Seattle, Washington. Volney Richmond, Jr. carries on his father's position as president of the Company.
In the 1868 articles of incorporation, the stated purposes of the Alaska Commercial Company were "...to buy, sell, rent and lease real estate...to erect buildings...to buy, sell, exchange..merchandise, stocks, bonds, franchises...to build tramways and roads...to catch and pack fish...to manufacture..." The Company established stations in Alaska at Nome, Kodiak, Sunrise, Eagle City, Circle City, St. Michael, Unga, Unalaska and others, and in Dawson in Canada, as well as various other Canadian stations.
Although the Northern Commercial Company became the new name of the Alaska Commercial Company in 1901, business was still carried on in the name of the Alaska Commercial Company as well, according to the papers and records in this collection of material. Among the papers of the company, both the Alaska Commercial Company and the Northern Commercial Company are involved, and volumes for the Alaska Commercial Company, the Northern Commercial Company and the Northern Navigation Company are included in the collection. From evidence accumulated through correspondence regarding this collection, the Alaska Commercial Company apparently did not cease doing business in its own name until 1942, leaving the Northern Commercial Company as the sole successor to the A.C.Co.
Provenance
Gift of Louis C. Greene, 1944 to Jackson Library and transferred to the Department of Special Collections in 1979.
Access Restrictions
None.
- Series 1. General Accounts: Papers, 1888 - 1940
  - Subseries A. Sundry Papers, 1888 - 1897
    - Sundry business papers, 1888 - 1894 Dec. 14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Sundry business papers, 1894 - 1895 May 3 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Sundry business papers, 1895 June - 1895 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Sundry business papers, 1896 - 1897 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Subseries B. Accounts, 1890 - 1939
    - Accounts H1 - H4, 1900 - 1904 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - H-1 Empire Transportation Co., SS "Portland", 1903 - 1904
      - H-2 List of Nome Steamer Records, 1904
      - H-3 G.C King & F.J. Lease to Wild Goose Mining and Trading Co., 1904
      - H-4 Mary C. Crowley, 1900 - 1904
    - Accounts H5 - H6, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - H-5 D.G. Barstow, 1901 - 1904
      - H-6 Schooner "Corinthian", 1904
    - Accounts H7 - H13, 1904 - 1905 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - H-7 James M. Rowan, 1904
      - H-8 Jesse C. Martin, 1904
      - H-9 Hop Wo Long & Co., 1905
      - H-10 Paul Buckley, 1905
      - H-11 Capt. J. M. Hays - stock, 1904
      - H-12 SS "St. Paul", 1905
      - H-13 SS "Portland" - survey report, 1905
    - Accounts H14 - H24, 1904 - 1906 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - H-14 Bark "Melanope", 1905-1906
      - H-15 American Bonding Co., 1905
      - H-16 D.J. Humphrey, 1905
      - H-17 John Shields, 1904
      - H-18 G.E. Noble, 1905
      - H-19 John I. White, 1905
      - H-20 Daniel Valpert, 1903-1905
      - H-21 Dr. Miles Medical Co., 1905
      - H-23 Queen City Laundry, 1905
      - H-24 School house- Wood Island, 1904-1905
    - Accounts H25 - H26, 1899 - 1907 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - H-25 Nicholas Christensen, 1901
      - H-26 Hank Summers, 1899-1907
    - Account H27: Schooner "Volant", 1905 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Accounts H29 - H30, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - H-27 Schooner "Volant", 1905
      - H-29 SS "Portland", 1905
      - H-30 Pacific States Telephone Co. contract, 1905
    - Accounts I2 - I6, 1904 - 1906 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - I-2 Mrs. Clovers, 1905
      - I-3 John J. Sesnon Co., 1904-1905
      - I-4 Adolph Wetzstein, 1905
      - I-5 H. Joseph -vs- Sarah Sloss & Hannah Gerstle, 1905
      - I-6 Seattle Station accounts, 1905-1906
    - Accounts I7 - I12, 1898 - 1906 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - I-7 SS "Farallon", 1906
      - I-8 Compressed Air Machinery Co., 1899
      - I-9 St. Michael- memon plant value, 1898-1902
      - I-10 Dawson station, 1902
      - I-11 SS "Fearless"- report, 1902-1907
      - I-12 Blanche Stull, 1906
    - Accounts I13 - I15, 1903 - 1907 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - I-13 Inventory of goods purchased from C.F. Yeaton at Sunrise station, 1907
      - I-14 Order list, "Apollo", 1907
      - I-15 H.A. Smith, 1903-1905
    - Accounts I16 - I17, 1906 - 1907 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - I-16 Plot of Forty Mile station and property owned by Alaska Commercial Co., 1907
      - I-17 Alaska Oil Co., 1906
    - Accounts 1 - 4, 1901 - 1906 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - 1. C.G. Van Hook- Eagle City, 1903-1905
      - 2. Capt. E.D. Dixon- Dawson, 1901-1903
      - 3. Capt. William C. Rogers- Circle City, 1902-1906
      - 4. Lt. B.J. Tillman- Eagle City, 1903-1906
    - Account 5: Anchor Point Mining Co. - Tyoonok, 1899 - 1905 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Account 6: Rev. N.P. Kashevaroff - Kodiak, 1903 - 1906 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Accounts 7 - 8, 1902 - 1904 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 7 Lagoon Packing Co. (F.N. McCandless), 1902-03
      - 8 Pond, Latham & Fairbanks- Dawson, 1902-1904
    - Account 9: Lt. W.M. Craigie - Nome and Eagle City, 1901 - 1906 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Account 10: G.L. Rickard - Dawson, 1903 - 1905 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Accounts 11 - 15, 1900 - 1905 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 11 Dr. J.L Bevans- open account, 1904-1905
      - 12 H.B.M. Miller-Dawson, 1903-1904
      - 13 Beach Bros.- Nome, 1900-1903
      - 14 H.M. Gracey- open account, 1901-1905
      - 15 James J. Carroll- Nome, 1900-1904
    - Accounts 16 - 18, 1900 - 1905 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - 16 J.P. O'Malley- Nome, 1903-1905
      - 17 Gunz- suspense account, 1903-1904
      - 18 Canadian Development Co.- Dawson, 1900-1904
    - Accounts 19 - 23, 1902 - 1906 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 19 Gordon Fraser- Dawson, 1902-1905
      - 20 H.C. Griffith- Nome, 1903
      - 21 J.H. Fredericks- Nome, 1903
      - 22 North West Mounted Police- Dawson, 1903-1906
    - Accounts 24 - 28, 1899 - 1905 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 24 George K. French- Eagle City, 1901-1905
      - 25 Peter Larsen- Unga, 1902-1903
      - 26 J.W. Burnham- Nome, 1903
      - 27 Post Exchange- Ft. Davis (Lt. K. Knudsen)- Nome, 1903
      - 28 A.T. Branson- Nome, 1899-1904
    - Accounts 29 - 32, 1903 - 1910 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - 29 Charles Hall- Forty Mile, 1903-1904
      - 30 C.E. Heron- Nome, 1903-1906
      - 31 Olaf Carlson- Kodiak, 1903-1907
      - 32 Charles Rosener and Rosener & Puttman-Nome, 1903-1910
    - Accounts 33 - 35, 1901 - 1906 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - 33 H.M. Libby- Eagle City, 1901-1904
      - 34 Mrs. J.J. Healy- Nome, 1903-1906
      - 35 Brynterson & Kjelsberg- Nome Water Co., 1901-1902
    - Accounts 36 - 37, 1900 - 1905 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - 36 Johnston & Reuben- St. Michael, 1900-1905
      - 37. E.R. Beeman (Beeman, Hubbard & Hume)- Nome, 1904-1905
    - Account 38: Major W.K. Wright - Eagle City, 1903 - 1904 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Accounts 39 - 40, 1902 - 1904 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - 39 Russian Church (Rev. Korchinsky)- St. Michael, 1902-1904
      - 40 S. Torgansen- Unga, 1902-1904
    - Accounts 41 - 42, 1901 - 1905 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - 41 Judge C.A. Dugas- Dawson, 1902-1905
      - 42 "Orizaba" Wreck account, 1901-1903
    - Account 43: G.W. Long- Unga, 1902 - 1903 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Accounts 44 - 47, 1898 - 1905 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - 44 Rev. J.R. Kapanadze- Kodiak, 1898-1905
      - 45 Alex W. Acheson- Dawson, 1903-1904
      - 46 J.B. Mullay- Nome, 1903-1904
      - 47 Jack Donovan- Nome, 1900-1903
    - Account 49, 1898 - 1905 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Scope and Contents note
      (Letters and papers arranged as they were originally rather than chronologically)
    - Accounts 52 - 57, 1902 - 1905 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 52 Fred Kottchoff -vs- A.C.Co., 1903
      - 53 M.F. Rowland, 1902-1903
      - 54 Holbrook Merrill & Stetson, 1903-1905
      - 55 Mrs. E. Montgomery et al -vs- A.C.Co., 1903
      - 57 Ezra Farnsworth- Sunrise, 1903
    - Account 58: Alaska Pacific Express Co., 1903 - 1904 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Accounts 59 - 62, 1903 - 1906 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - 58 Alaska Pacific Express Co., 1903-1904
      - 59 North American Commercial Co. -vs- P.R. Temple estate, 1903-1904
      - 60 Cook Inlet Transportation Co.- Tyoonak, 1903-1904
      - 61 George C. Mayon, 1903-1905
      - 62 Internal Revenue Bankers tax claim for refund, 1903-1906
    - Account 63: U.S. Commissiary Dept., 1900 - 1903 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Accounts 64 - 68, 1899 - 1905 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - 64 U.S. Transport Seward, 1904
      - 65 Lt. Lowe Exploring Expedition- Forty Mile, 1904
      - 66 USS "Nunivak", 1903-1904
      - 67 Mail trip- Tyoonak tSunrise, 1902-1904
      - 68 Transportation of merchandise, 1899-1905
    - Accounts 69 - 70, 1899 - 1904 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - 69 Transportation of indigent citizens from Alaska, 1899-1904
      - 70 Frank E. Lee- Eagle City tSan Francisc, 1901-1904
    - Account 71: F.L. Bates- Postmaster- Circle City, 1899-1902 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Account 72: McNaught Barge account, 1906 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Account 74: Salvage of the bark "Mermaid", 1900-1904 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Account 75: Wood vouchers in hands of J.S. Webb [1 of 3], 1900-1903 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Account 75: Wood vouchers in hands of J.S. Webb [2 of 3], 1900-1903 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Account 75: Wood vouchers in hands of J.S. Webb [3 of 3], 1900-1903 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Account 76: U.S. Marshall- Nome account for coal, 1900-1904 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Accounts 77 - 78, 1899 - 1903 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - 77 Rent U.S. jail- Circle City, 1899-1902
      - 78 Cook Inlet Mining claims- Sunrise, 1900-1903
    - Accounts 79 - 82, 1898 - 1906 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - 79 Esquinox Mining Co.- Nome, 1903
      - 80 Miss M.A. Julian (now Mrs. Crow)-, 1898-1904
      - 81 W.B. McCubbin matter, 1902-1903
      - 82 W.H. Emerson, 1900-1906
    - Accounts 83 - 86, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 83 Olaf A. Hansen, 1903
      - 84 Irwin Brothers, 1903
      - 85 J.W. Charlton, 1903
      - 86 W.P. Day, 1903
    - Account 87: George Melse -vs- SS "Bertha" and others [1 of 5], 1903 - 1905 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Account 87: George Melse -vs- SS "Bertha" and others [2 of 5], 1903 - 1905 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Account 87: George Melse -vs- SS "Bertha" and others [3 of 5], 1903 - 1905 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Account 87: George Melse -vs- SS "Bertha" and others [4 of 5], 1903 - 1905 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Account 87: George Melse -vs- SS "Bertha" and others [5 of 5], 1903 - 1905 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Accounts 88 - 90, 1903 - 1904 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - 88 John J. Lesnon Co., 1903-1904
      - 89 De SotMining Co., 1903
      - 90 Charles S. Johnson, 1901-1903
    - Accounts 91 - 93, 1900 - 1903 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - 91 L.G. Dolson, 1900-1902
      - 92 R. McArthur, 1902
      - 93 A. Dinkelspiel, 1902-1903
    - Accounts 94 - 96, 1900 - 1901 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - 94 Katherine Kennedy, 1900-1901
      - 95 J.W. Connell, 1900-1901
      - 96 Emma Lines -vs- A.C.Co., 1901
    - Accounts 97 - 100, 1901 - 1904 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - 97 Sam Dannenbaum -vs- A.C.Co., 1901
      - 98 Tanana Lumber Co., 1903-1904
      - 99 J.F. Watson- Nome, 1904
      - 100 Mrs. M. Miller, 1903
    - Accounts 101 - 104, 1898 - 1906 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - 101 H.S. Tibbey, 1903-1904
      - 102 A.F. Ziph- St. Michael, 1901-1903
      - 103 De Witt Gray, 1898-1905
      - 104 A.F. Genest, 1898-1906
    - Accounts 105 - 107, 1898 - 1904 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - 105 W.H. Ferguson- De SotPlacer Mining Co., 1903-1904
      - 106 Capt. C.A. Knudsen, 1903-1904
      - 107 "Sundry old drafts, etc." (A-P), 1898-1899
    - Accounts 108 - 112, 1898 - 1905 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - 108 Sundry notices of protest, 1898-1905
      - 109 SS "St. Paul", 1902-1905
      - 110 George R. Voss, 1904
      - 111 Dr. S.J. Call, 1901-1902
      - 112 Walter J. King, 1903-1904
    - Account 113: William J. Henry, 1900-1902 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Account 114: Drew Coal Mine, 1899-1904 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Account 115: Pickarts, Bettles & Pickarts, 1899-1902 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Account 116: Wheaton & Dunham- Nome, 1900-1901 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Account 117 - 122, 1901 - 1904 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - 117 G.W. Gilbert- Nome, 1903-1904
      - 118 Louis Jaccard- Dawson, 1904
      - 119 Louis Hanisch- Circle City, 1903-1904
      - 120 R.R. Lowe, 1904
      - 121 C.T. Malcolm- Nome, 1900-1904
      - 122 Russian Mission, 1901
    - Account 123 - 128, 1899 - 1904 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - 123 V.E. Burrows- Dawson, 1902
      - 124 Joseph F. Evans-St. Michael, 1900
      - 125 Peter Johnson- Unga, 1899
      - 126 Du Val, C.R.- Nome, 1901-1904
      - 127 Mail route # 78090, 1903-1904
      - 128 George Barrett- Kodiak, 1904
    - Account 129 - 130, 1904 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - 129 F.L. Hawley- Circle City, 1904
      - 130 SS "Portland", 1904
    - Account 131 - 134, 1904 - 1906 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - 132 SS "Portland", 1904
      - 133 Jeremiah Cousby- Nome, 1904-1905
      - 134 Instructions tpursers, 1904-1906
    - Account 135 - 137, 1903 - 1906 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - 135 T.L. Brevig- Nome, 1903-1904
      - 136 A.C. Barry, trustee (William and Olga Brown), 1901-1906
      - 137 Pacific Coast Steamship Co., 1904
    - Account 138 - 140, 1903 - 1905 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - 138 "Bowery Claim"- G.W. Long, 1903-1904
      - 139 A. Fredericks- St. Michael, 1904
      - 140 Semedi Propogating Co., 1904-1905
    - Account 141 - 143, 1904 - 1906 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - 141 Standard Oil Co., 1904
      - 142 George V. Borchsenius, 1904-1905
      - 143 Archer Ewing & Co. -vs- A.C.Co., 1904
    - Account 144: SS "Schwatka", 1904 - 1905 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Account 145: Brooklyn Institute of Art & Science- Kodiak, 1904 - 1905 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Accounts 146 - 148, 1904 - 1905 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - 146 Henry Doyle & Co., 1905
      - 147 Alaska Mining and Development Co., 1904-1905
      - 148 Sunrise Station claim against Cook Inlet Transportation Co., 1905
    - Accounts 149 - 151, 1901 - 1915 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - 149 A. Belkoff- St. Michael, 1901-1915
      - 150 H.S. Tibby- Unga, 1905
      - 151 Lt. A.M. Wetherell, 1904-1905
    - Account 152: Kodiak School and teachers, 1890-1907 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Accounts 152A - 153, 1905 - 1912 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - 152a Kodiak School vouchers; teachers' supplies and salaries, 1908-1912
      - 153 John Moberg, 1905
    - Accounts 154 - 158, 1900 - 1905 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - 154 Chris Brelich, 1904-1905
      - 156 A.G. Griggs, 1905
      - 157 J.F. Burke and G.E. Burke, 1905
      - 158 J.L. Watson, 1900-1905
    - Accounts 159 - 160, 1905 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - 159 SS "Melville Dollar", 1905
      - 160 SS "Dirigo", 1905
    - Account 161: George H. Melse case appeal (see # 87 for previous records), 1905-1906 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Accounts 162 - 164, 1902-1906 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - 162 Northwestern Steamship Co., 1905
      - 163 Jacobson & Thorstensen -vs- A.C.Co., 1905-06
      - 164 Robert J. Mann, 1902-1906
    - Accounts 165 - 168, 1905-1906 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - 165 Lease of Wilson Hotel, 1906
      - 166 Alaska Codfish Co., 1906
      - 167 C.C. Lutjens, 1906
      - 168 "Meteor Coal", 1905-1906
    - Accounts 169: Traders Insurance Co., 1906 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Accounts 171: "Santa Ana" matters, 1906-1909 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Accounts 172 - 173, 1906-1909 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - 172 "Oregon" Wreck matters, 1906
      - 173 Sophia Reniken sundry receipts, 1901-1906
    - Accounts 174 - 175, 1904-1907 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - 174 "Bertha" and "Portland"- sundry papers, 1904-1907
      - 175 Ralph J. Long, 1906
    - Accounts 176 - 177, 1900-1907 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - 176 Ike Powers, 1900-1902
      - 177 Indemity bond and sundry letters-Northwest Mounted Police, 1907
    - Accounts 179: "Bertha" and "Portland", 1906 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Accounts 180 - 182, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - 180 SS "Duneric", 1907
      - 181 Seattle Shipping Co., 1907
      - 182 Schooner "Bender Bros.", 1907
    - Account 183: Land titles- Kodiak, 1910-1924 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Accounts 184 - 189, 1904 - 1908 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - 184 Agreement for season 1907; Cook Inlet Transportation Co.
      - 185 SS "Transit", 1907
      - 186 Susitna Station, 1904-1908
      - 187 Sale of lots at Forty Mile, 1905-1908
      - 188 Douglas Kyle, 1905-1907
      - 189 Agreement with Alaska Codfish Co., 1908
    - Account 190: Henry Dirks- agreement with A.C.Co., 1908-1910 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Accounts 200 - 209, 1905 - 1908 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - 200 Confirmation of Revenue Cutter, 1908
      - 201 Mr. Bankowski, 1908
      - 202 American schooner "Commerce", 1908
      - 203 American schooner "Babcock", 1908
      - 204 Schooner "C.S. Holmes", 1908
      - 205 "M.S. Dollar", 1908
      - 206 Schooner "Lizzie Prien"-bill of sale, 1908-1910
      - 207 Annie Hemmingway, 1908
      - 208 Fredora Clark estate, 1908
      - 209 Mrs. Pederzam, 1905
    - Accounts 210 - 212, 1908 - 1913 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - 210 "Lizzie Prien"- damage, 1908
      - 211 Coal drawback, 1908
      - 212 Frank R. Brown, 1908-1913
    - Account 213: Alaska Pacific Steamship Co., 1907 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Account 214 - 215, 1908 - 1914 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - 214 Agreements: A.C.Co. and Cook Inlet Transportation Co., 1909
      - 215 Louis Sloss and A.C.Co. - agreement, 1908 - 1914
    - Accounts 216 - 219, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - 216 Puget Sound Tugboat Co., 1909
      - 217 Strauss & Hedges, 1909
      - 218 Crow Creek property, 1909
      - 219 Alaska Steamship Co., Alaska Coast Co., 1909
    - Account 220: Stolen furs (Sam Applegate property), 1908 - 1909 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Accounts 221 - 223, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - 221 Indemnity bond, 1909
      - 223 "Ida McKay", 1909
    - Accounts 224 - 229, 1909 - 1910 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - 224 Treasury department and coal, 1909
      - 225 United Wireless Telegraph Co., 1909
      - 226 Barge "Quatsino", 1909
      - 227 Applications for liquor license, 1909
      - 228 Revenue Cutter service, 1909-1910
      - 229 "Tyonic" and "Tonquiu"- certificates of registry, 1908-1909
    - Accounts 230 -234, 1908 - 1913 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - 230 "Valdz", 1908
      - 231 Power of attorney- Lilienthal and Sloss tM.L. Washburn, 1909
      - 232 "Ohio" loss, 1909-1913
      - 234 Schooner "San Buena Ventura", 1909
    - Accounts 236 -237, 1908 - 1911 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - 236 Affidavit- J.A. Silverman, 1909
      - 237 Lease and purchase- North American Transportation and Trading Co., 1908-1911
    - Accounts 238 - 242, 1895 - 1913 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - 238 Bill of sale- "Tyonic", 1910-1913
      - 239 Bill of sale- "Tonquiu", 1909
      - 240 Bill of sale- "S.B. Mathews", 1895-1911
      - 241 Contract purchase-coal, from North American Commercial Co., 1910
      - 242 Schooner "Lettie", 1910
    - Accounts 243 - 246, 1909 - 1910 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - 243 Operation of "Tyonic" and "Alice", 1910
      - 244 Power of attorney- A.C.Co. tIra D. Orton, 1910
      - 245 Alaska Garage Building, 1909-1910
      - 246 "Ottillie Fjord", 1910